WALAA ISTAITIEH

MSc PETROLEUM ENGINEER

Dear,

Recently graduated from Heriot-Watt University, UK as a M.Sc. Petroleum Engineer with 'Production Optimization Employing Smart Wells' and 'North Sea development plan' as a graduate projects. Moreover, I got my Bachelor Degree in Mechatronics Engineering with excellent and honoured degree and 'Hydro-motor powered racing car' and 'CNC milling machine' as a graduate projects.

I'm seeking to join your company for an engineering role. In my career I was focusing on projects related to reservoir characterization, well engineering, reservoir management and project management with knowledge and understanding of applicable science and possesses awareness of existing and emerging technology within oil/gas industry. Able to create an effectively plan and manage workload to meet desired timelines, deliverables and service level targets with higher quality under safety regulations.

Over the last three years, I owned my technical skills by reading manuals and implement it on a wide range of projects at Schlumberger and University both individually and in large teams. Recently, I have developed my managerial abilities and leading technical talks by working as a President at SPE (Society of Petroleum Engineering) by coordinating technical talks with oil/gas leading companies such as Shell, Total and GE.

I have been told by others that I have a boundless energy, a great presentation skills and extremely clever.

My long term goal is to do a PhD. Degree in real-time reservoir management.

Teaching, research, analysis, programming and new development are my core area.

If you are looking for focus, organized, highly motivated and interpolated mind-set then I'm your candidate.

Sincerely,

Walaa Istaitieh



CONTACT

© 00973 35911578

@ walaasaeed8@gmail.com

Manama, Bahrain

SOCIAL MEDIA

in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/walaaistaitieh-041891146/

(

https://www.instagram.com/lifestyleengineerle/

S live: walaasaeed8

LANGUAGES

Arabic, native
English, IELTS 7

SKILLS (TECHNOLOGY/FUNCTIOINAL)

- Reservoir Simulation (ECLIPSE)
- Reservoir Management techniques
- Formation Evaluation (TechLog)
- Production Technology (WellFlo)
- SQL, C++ and Matlab programming
- Petroleum Economics (SWOT analysis, calculating NPV, OPEX, CAPEX AND MCO
- HSE management
- Primavera P6, MS project
- Oracle business
- ❖ API & ASME standards

B WALAA ISTAITIEH

MSc PETROLEUM ENGINEER

B OBJECTIVE

Successfully managed and controlled projects cost and progress represented in Capital and Operational expenditures, within the allocated budget, starting from project initiation till the close out phase. Able to carry out various financial and variance analysis to produce recovery plans. Moreover, able to apply appropriate advanced techniques to solve non-routine problems, influences decisions affecting analytical procedures and capital commitment. Analysis, research and new developments are my core area.

EDUCATION

Heriot Watt University

2017 - 2021

UK - Edinburgh

MSc Petroleum Engineering

Masters' Thesis: Production optimization employing smart wells & North Sea Field development plan.

October 6 University

2009 - 2013

Cairo – Egypt

B.Sc. Mechatronics Engineering (Excellent With Honors)

Bachelor Thesis: "Race car powered by Hydro-engine/Water Engine (patented in the Academy of Science) & automatic spray painting (CNC).

EXPERIENCE

SPE (society of petroleum engineers)

Oct 2017- Sep 2018

President of student chapter for Heriot-Watt University

Technical talk's leader.

Schlumberger Middle East (SLB)

Aug 2013 - Apr 2015

Field Specialist

- Manage field operations, including engineering design, maintenance, job planning, and operational reporting.
- Production operations, risk assessment, well Intervention: Wireline, Coiled Tubing, and Testing.
- Real-time Well Control during well intervention.

Engineering Academy Institute

Jan 2010 - Jun 2013

Instructor of Industrial Automation / Technical support

- Manufacturing, design, PLC programming, controlling systems and technical support for factory embedded systems.
- HMI, SCADA, PLC and LabVIEW instructor.

№ COURSES

Well testing, Petrel, Eclipse, CMG, tNav, Matlab, C++, Mastering of solids work, Risk Assessment, QHSE, Microsoft project, Projects Management, Marketing Specialist, Coaching and Developing and Operational Excellence.

M HOBBIES AND INTRESTS

Reading, diving and programming.

REFRENCES & CERTIFICATIONS

Upon request